<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bo Gao&#39;s Homepage (BJTU) on Bo Gao&#39;s Homepage (BJTU)</title>
    <link>https://bgao-vt.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bo Gao&#39;s Homepage (BJTU) on Bo Gao&#39;s Homepage (BJTU)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017-2019 Bo Gao</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectrum Sharing Among Rapidly Deployable Small Cells: A Hybrid Multi-Agent Approach (IEEE TWC 2020)</title>
      <link>https://bgao-vt.github.io/publication/twc_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bgao-vt.github.io/publication/twc_20/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acceptance to IEEE TWC</title>
      <link>https://bgao-vt.github.io/post/twc_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bgao-vt.github.io/post/twc_20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper titled &amp;ldquo;Spectrum Sharing Among Rapidly Deployable Small Cells: A Hybrid Multi-Agent Approach&amp;rdquo; has been accepted to the IEEE Transactions on Wireless Communications! Please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://bgao-vt.github.io/#publications_selected&#34;&gt;Publications&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Resource Allocation for Mass Event Hotspots</title>
      <link>https://bgao-vt.github.io/project/rdsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bgao-vt.github.io/project/rdsc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the era of 5G mobile communications and Internet of Things (IoT), each macro-cell can be densely overlaid with small cells, so that mobile users or connected things are served by a heterogeneous network (HetNet). It is straightforward to deploy small cells for indoor hotspots such as homes or offices, but usually not for outdoor hotspots to support, e.g., public gatherings or sporting events. As the use of wireless devices outdoors is becoming a daily necessity, it has received a growing interest in augmenting macro-cell coverage for target spots that are wide-open yet short-lived. A further improvement of outdoor coverage is necessary when user devices are brought together in a short time and cause a burst increase in macro-cell traffic, thus leading to a supply-demand mismatch. It commonly occurs that lots of user devices are temporarily gathered for broadband or IoT services. However, it can be very costly or even impossible to fully and persistently cover an outdoor hotspot with small cells. Recently, a promising innovation is to mount small base stations (SBSs) on movable and controllable platforms, such as unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) or unmanned ground vehicles (UGVs). Under vehicular mobility, UAV/UGV-mounted small cells are rapidly deployable in case macro-cell base stations (MBSs) are overloaded, or even damaged or destroyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On-demand deployment of UAV/UGV-mounted small cells plays a key role in augmenting macro-cell coverage for outdoor hotspots, but the issues of dynamic resource allocation have to be emphasized in the uplink. For example, a typical downlink-to-uplink ratio of mobile devices is 10:1, but it can become 1:3 during mass events along with a tenfold increase in uplink traffic, due to the popularity of social media. To handle intensive uploading of user/machine-generated data, limited wireless spectrum has to be shared and reused by small cells efficiently and effectively. Therefore, organizing a two-tier HetNet outdoors necessitates inter-cell spectrum sharing, and we mainly focus on co-tier spectrum sharing among small cells. This is different from a typical scenario in that network performance is valued more in the uplink than in the downlink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we have to address the following challenges. First, our approach has to jointly optimize small cell deployment and uplink resource allocation. In addition to the 3D placement of movable small cells to cover an outdoor hotspot, it is also necessary to study the establishment of uplink transmissions to meet user needs. Specifically, the problem of inter-cell spectrum sharing involves decision making on four aspects, including small cell placement, user-cell association, channel resource allocation, and transmit power control. Second, our approach has to be responsive to initially unknown and varying demands of user devices for uplink transmissions. It is common in an outdoor hotspot that movable small cells can only selectively fulfill a part of user demands for a limited period of time, but the distribution of user demands is not known a priori and is even ever-changing. Thus, the joint optimization problem has to be solved in a user-centric, online manner. Third, our approach has to be applicable to a resource-constrained cellular system. Although the base stations in two tiers of a HetNet can work as decision-making entities, the user-centric, online joint optimization to be performed can be too complex for either an MBS or an SBS. Any entity can suffer from limited computing, energy, and storage resources. Besides, it is already hard to derive a real-time solution to such a complex problem even given sufficient resources.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visit to Lancaster University</title>
      <link>https://bgao-vt.github.io/post/lancaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bgao-vt.github.io/post/lancaster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I will be visiting Lancaster University, UK from Oct. 2018 to Jul. 2019, for the international partnership between BJTU and LU. In the following years, I am  expected to teach two modules&amp;mdash;&amp;ldquo;Artificial Intelligence&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Embedded Systems&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;in the Lancaster University College, a joint institute located at our Weihai campus.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Grant from NSFC</title>
      <link>https://bgao-vt.github.io/post/nsfc_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bgao-vt.github.io/post/nsfc_18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have recently received a new research grant from the National Natural Science Foundation of China (NSFC)! This project addresses the issues of resource allocation in radio access networks for mass event hotspots. Please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://bgao-vt.github.io/#projects&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fog Computing-Assisted Energy-Efficient Resource Allocation for High-Mobility MIMO-OFDMA Networks (WCMC 2018)</title>
      <link>https://bgao-vt.github.io/publication/wcmc_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bgao-vt.github.io/publication/wcmc_18/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preserving Incumbent Users&#39; Privacy in Exclusion-Zone-Based Spectrum Access Systems (IEEE ICDCS 2017)</title>
      <link>https://bgao-vt.github.io/publication/icdcs_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bgao-vt.github.io/publication/icdcs_17/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acceptance to IEEE ICDCS 2017</title>
      <link>https://bgao-vt.github.io/post/icdcs_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bgao-vt.github.io/post/icdcs_17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper titled &amp;ldquo;Preserving Incumbent Users&amp;rsquo; Privacy in Exclusion-Zone-Based Spectrum Access Systems&amp;rdquo; has been accepted to the IEEE ICDCS 2017 Short Papers track! Please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://bgao-vt.github.io/#publications_selected&#34;&gt;Publications&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TESSO: An Analytical Tool for Characterizing Aggregate Interference and Enabling Spatial Spectrum Sharing (IEEE DySPAN 2017)</title>
      <link>https://bgao-vt.github.io/publication/dyspan_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bgao-vt.github.io/publication/dyspan_17/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P2-SAS: Privacy-Preserving Centralized Dynamic Spectrum Access System (IEEE JSAC 2017)</title>
      <link>https://bgao-vt.github.io/publication/jsac_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bgao-vt.github.io/publication/jsac_17/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acceptance to IEEE DySPAN 2017</title>
      <link>https://bgao-vt.github.io/post/dyspan_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bgao-vt.github.io/post/dyspan_17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper titled &amp;ldquo;TESSO: An Analytical Tool for Characterizing Aggregate Interference and Enabling Spatial Spectrum Sharing&amp;rdquo; has been accepted to the IEEE DySPAN 2017 technology track! Please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://bgao-vt.github.io/#publications_selected&#34;&gt;Publications&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acceptance to IEEE JSAC</title>
      <link>https://bgao-vt.github.io/post/jsac_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bgao-vt.github.io/post/jsac_16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper titled &amp;ldquo;P2-SAS: Privacy-Preserving Centralized Dynamic Spectrum Access System&amp;rdquo; has been accepted to the IEEE Journal on Selected Areas in Communications (JSAC), Special Issue on Spectrum Sharing and Aggregation for Future Wireless Networks! Please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://bgao-vt.github.io/#publications_selected&#34;&gt;Publications&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acceptance to IEEE TCCN</title>
      <link>https://bgao-vt.github.io/post/tccn_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bgao-vt.github.io/post/tccn_16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper titled &amp;ldquo;An Overview of Dynamic Spectrum Sharing: Ongoing Initiatives, Challenges, and a Roadmap for Future Research&amp;rdquo; has been accepted to the IEEE Transactions on Cognitive Communications and Networking (TCCN)! Please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://bgao-vt.github.io/#publications_selected&#34;&gt;Publications&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P2-SAS: Preserving Users&#39; Privacy in Centralized Dynamic Spectrum Access Systems (ACM MobiHoc 2016)</title>
      <link>https://bgao-vt.github.io/publication/mobihoc_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bgao-vt.github.io/publication/mobihoc_16/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Overview of Dynamic Spectrum Sharing: Ongoing Initiatives, Challenges, and a Roadmap for Future Research (IEEE TCCN 2016)</title>
      <link>https://bgao-vt.github.io/publication/tccn_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bgao-vt.github.io/publication/tccn_16/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
